THE ORDEAL
Day after day , life is merely survival
Your pockets are empty before month 's end
What a strange period
Crises are myriad
Since love is our only way out
And union creates the beds of thousands
I propose
A plan as sweet as a rose
Bring , bring your week
To mine
That 'll give the two of us
Fifteen days of bliss
We 'll keep a tight rein
On our purse and tenderness
Loving eyes
That could last forever
Bring , bring your week
To mine
That 'll give the two of us
Fifteen days of bliss
We 'll be together
Head and legs
All life long
We 'll be fifty-fifty !
Merry Christmas to all !
I 'm so happy to see you again !
Soon , a new year will begin .
A new year that will surely be full of happiness
and good times . A year of joy and delight ,
but most of all , a year full of songs ...
Love songs , of course !
Yes , come in .
Come in .
Please sit down .
I 'm almost done taking off my makeup .
Marc , you bring us so much joy each time .
Thank you , Mrs. Langhoff . Can I do something for you ?
Your songs
bring me back to my youth ,
bring back memories .
You know ,
next year ,
I may no longer be here when you return .
Don 't say such things ! Of course you 'll be here .
Can I ask you a favor ?
Of course , anything you 'd like ...
But you were looking at me during the show .
I 'm sorry .
I don 't know what came over me .
Excuse me .
How could you have done that ?
You dirty whore !
Old fucking slut !
Look what you did . You ruined everything ! Everything !
What are you going to do now ?
I 'm going south for a Christmas gala .
There 'll be some producers .
I hope you 'll return when you 'll be a star !
Of course I 'll come back .
Everyone loves you a lot here . You know that ?
Well , I should get going ...
Yes , of course .
Thank you very much .
Ok then ...
Can I hug you before you leave ?
I 'm going to miss you .
Please let me go now , miss .
I have to go .
BARTEL INN 3 KM
Have you seen a dog ?
A dog with short hair .
A dog about this big with short hair ?
Excuse me ?
I 'm looking for my dog .
I saw something dash out ...
I can 't tell you if it was a dog or not .
You saw it ?
I said I saw something cross the road , but I don 't ...
Really ? Which way did it go ?
I think it went that way .
That way ...
Bella !
Hey , come back !
Young man , come back !
Come back !
My name is Boris .
Ok , Boris , can you help me ?
My van broke down and I saw a sign saying there was an inn .
An inn ? It 's not too far from here .
But I have to find Bella .
Tell me where it is , that 's all I 'm asking .
Could you tell me where the inn is , please ?
Follow me , but don 't make any noise .
I have to be able to hear Bella !
I can 't just leave my van in the middle of the road !
I asked you not to make any noise .
Are you sure I can leave my van there ?
Are we almost there ?
I said not to make noise and it means shutting your mouth !
Mr. Bartel !
I 've brought you someone .
He 'll come down and open the door .
I 've brought you someone . He wants a room .
Good evening .
Sorry to wake you , but my van broke down ...
It 's fine , come in .
Nobody 's been here for a long time , but the rooms are clean .
Here it is .
Goodnight .
Did the singer sleep well ?
Very well , thank you .
I took the liberty of towing your van .
I 'm handy with cars , so if I could be of help ...
Thanks , but ...
Come on , it 's normal between colleagues !
I saw the inscription .
Get out of the way , please .
" Performer-Singer " . I 'm also a performer !
Well , I used to be a comic !
Once a performer , always a performer . I was more so before ...
You didn 't tow my van with the hand brake on ?
So , we ' re , as one would say ... Colleagues !
I 'm gonna make your breakfast and take care of the van afterwards .
Couldn 't we call a mechanic ? I don 't want to bother you .
There must be a mechanic in the area ?
- We could call ... - Shut up !
I really wish he 'd find his dog .
He hasn 't been the same since he lost her .
Do you have a telephone at your inn ?
May I take a look ?
You have a telephone , don 't you ?
- Excuse me ? - I asked if you have a telephone .
Of course , I have a telephone !
I 'm not a savage ! What do you think ?
Oh really ? Goodness ...
My word ...
And when 's he coming back ?
This afternoon ?
Maybe ? But is it maybe or for sure ?
Ok , very well . Thank you , goodbye .
- It was his wife . - So ?
He 's working off premises . Looks like he 'll be busy all day .
Don 't worry ! I 'm handy with cars . I 'll take a look .
What 's the hurry ?
Well , I have long ways to drive .
- Where are you going ? - To the south . A Christmas gala .
Christmas !
But you still have two days !
Performers must recharge their batteries !
A little rest will do you good !
You 're probably right .
I 'll make you a nice breakfast ,
and then I 'll take a look at your van .
Thank you , sir .
Bartel ! Call me Bartel .
Not " sir " among performers !
Ok , Bartel !
Have a seat .
Can I help you ?
No , no ...
I bet you know nothing about mechanics !
True , I admit it .
That 's what I thought . I 'll take care of it . Just relax .
I 'm going to take a little walk .
Let me give you some advice ...
don 't go down to the village .
Why not ?
Those people are not like you and me .
They 're not performers .
So , be kind enough not to go .
Ok , but tell me why ...
They all are ...
They can ...
They are all ...
Calm down , Bartel ! I won 't go to the village .
- You promise ? - Yes , I promise .
See you later .
Have a nice walk , pal !
Be careful ! The paths are slippery this time of year .
You make me crazy ...
Marc , we love you ...
Marc , come back soon ...
Oh Marc , if you only knew ...
I 'm burning with desire ...
It 's good . It 's tender .
Go on , son .
Come on , little man !
What am I supposed to do ? You 're really funny !
I never said it was your fault !
Yes , ok ...
So , how was your walk ?
It sure is a beautiful region .
You went down to the village !
No , I just walked around here .
So , what 's the latest ?
I 've had trouble with your van .
The machinery is fine . I think it 's the battery .
I spoke with the mechanic 's wife . It can be fixed but ...
- not before tomorrow . - Tomorrow ?
Yeah , that 's what I said ! " Why not Easter ! "
Well , I 'm going to try to start it up .
Marc , wait !
Wait !
It won 't start up !
I spent all afternoon working on it .
Trust me !
Don 't be so obstinate !
I understand that you ' re disappointed , I understand but ...
I 'm going to prepare you a good dinner !
You 'll taste the Bartel cuisine
and I promise you 'll be off tomorrow !
Here ,
potatoes , bacon and cream au gratin .
A specialty of the house !
Well , it used to be ...
At the time when the inn was still very active ...
You know , we used to attract many people , mainly performers .
Well , now that Gloria has gone , it 's not the same .
Gloria , my wife .
- You 're married ? - When I say " my wife " ...
She left me .
She was a singer like you .
What talent !
If you had heard her ...
I didn 't want to upset you .
Well , how could you have known ?
So , what do you have against the villagers ?
If you could have heard her sing ... She was a wonder !
That woman was everything for me .
By losing her , I lost everything .
Now you understand how happy I am to be in the company of an artist .
I 'm gonna show you something .
Look , it 's inscribed , " First Prize " .
I won it thanks to my sense of humor .
But when Gloria left ,
Bartel 's sense of humor left with her .
Finished , over .
Bartel 's fantasy !
However , when Gloria was here ,
I was happy as a lark . I was always singing to myself ,
joking around .
I was always telling jokes . Here 's one ...
There 's this dwarves ' association
who decides to create a football club .
So , they meet every Sunday
at a café where they have drinks after the game .
So , one day , there 's a guy at the bar ...
He 's already somewhat drunk
and he sees two dwarves come down the stairs in blue jerseys .
Then , three , four , five , ten ...
eleven !
He wonders if he 's not hallucinating !
He asks for another whisky , and suddenly , he sees more dwarves
come down the stairs in red jerseys . Two , three , five , eleven !
He orders another whisky and subtly calls the café owner over ...
" I don 't want to worry you but
" the table-football players are running away ! "
" The table-football players are running away ! "
It 's a good one , huh ?
And I didn 't even tell it well .
No , because back in the days ...
you 'd be rolling on the floor .
And you know why ?
Enthusiasm !
Yes , it 's enthusiasm , I 'm telling you !
At a show enthusiasm is essential .
In fact , when Gloria left ,
I decided to drown myself in my work .
I decided to write a treaty :
" The notion of enthusiasm in the principles of humor . "
That 's the title I chose , and then ,
I didn 't finish it .
I didn 't finish it , because , you see ...
when a woman leaves you , it screws everything up .
Listen , it was really good .
You know , I have a long drive tomorrow , so I 'm going to bed .
Already ?
So you ' re going to leave without singing me something !
Excuse me ?
Sing me something to give me insight
into your talent ...
I don 't know . It 's late and I 'm tired .
Don 't make me beg ! Especially between artists .
I told you my joke , didn 't I ?
Ok , but I don 't know what to sing . Without music ...
Improvise !
A love song . Love songs are always good .
I told you enthusiasm is what counts .
Like a rose from the month of May
You received youth and beauty
While in the shadows , I stare at my life
I see so many faces sparkling with desire
You are too beautiful and sensual
For a boy like me
I have a simple dream of serene happiness
That you won 't give ...
- There you go ! - What ? That 's it ?
I didn 't tell you half a joke .
You have to finish it !
You are too beautiful and trifles
Are not enough for me
I 'd like to give you my bed
But for my whole life long
Even a dove
Happy in its nest
Sometimes flies away forever towards infinity
I 'm afraid for us
For right or for wrong
That you 'll fly away one day
Towards other horizons
You are too beautiful and too sensual
For a boy like me
I have a simple dream of serene happiness
That you won 't give
You are too beautiful and trifles
Are not enough for me
I 'd like to give you my bed
But for my whole life long
That 's it .
I 'm going to bed .
Can I count on you to wake me up ?
Marc !
Thanks for this wonderful moment ...
Bartel ?
Is someone here ?
Bella !
Boris !
I 'm looking for Bartel .
- Do you hear me ? - Leave me alone !
Please answer me , have you seen him ?
- I 'll never find my girlie ! - Who ?
Bella ! My dog !
Sorry about your dog , but have you seen Bartel ?
She is all alone in the forest !
And it 's so terribly cold out !
Listen , I 'm looking for Bartel !
Lost !
She must be so scared !
Can I help you ?
The door was open ...
So , I thought ...
I went to the village . I ordered a battery for your van .
The mechanic won 't be long . A little more patience ...
You didn 't wake me up and there 's a problem with my van .
I didn 't wake you up because you were sound asleep .
I 'm not used to waking people who are sound asleep .
You found it ?
You left it on the table last night .
I was going to return it ...
What are you doing ?
What 's wrong with you ?
Stop !
Calm down ! I 'm not going to hurt you !
Is this what you 're looking for ?
Why leave if you came back ?
You ' re going to crush my heart again ?
What the hell are you doing ?
I won 't say anything to anyone !
Just let me go !
See ...
it 's better when you don 't move your head .
I 'm doing this to protect you .
I don 't enjoy making you look ugly .
It hurts me as much as it hurts you .
I 'm happy too !
You 'll see , this will be the best Christmas ever !
Where is my axe ?
You know , my axe with the oak handle ?
You should know things like that !
You have the oddest way of putting things away !
There it is ! You 're going to see ...
We 'll get the most beautiful tree and you 'll decorate it !
You always liked to decorate the tree ... those stars and balls .
That 's your thing !
Hey , let me tell you something ...
if you try to leave me again ,
I 'll split you in two like a log !
Ok ...
Here we go !
Do you have your ticket ?
Step right up !
Ferris wheels ! Carnivals !
Do you hear Bartel laughing ?
This enthusiasm is all thanks to you !
Let 's go !
Let 's get this show on the road !
See ? Just like a young man !
That bitch !
That fucking bitch !
That dirty fucking bitch !
Gloria !
Gloria , what the hell !
Is someone there ?
Boris ?
Daddy promised Bella that he 'd find her .
Bella won 't stay alone in the forest .
Untie me .
Untie me !
I 'm sorry , sorry !
Come back , Boris !
There you go , Mr. Bartel .
Don 't look so sad , Boris !
You 're going to find your sweet doggy !
You just have to be obstinate . That 's the only way !
Obstinacy is the key to everything .
So , Boris , are you going back with us ?
No , I 'm going to be obstinate , like you said .
You 're utterly right to be obstinate !
I have to run now !
No , no !
You see what you make me do !
Sometimes I wonder what you ' re thinking !
It 's no fun for me either , but it works !
As for you ...
don 't forget that I know !
I forgave you , but I know exactly what 's going on !
A beer !
Two beers .
I said a beer !
I 'm here to warn you !
No one will prevent me from being happy !
All I want is to live in peace .
Am I clear ?
The first one who makes a move on my wife is dead !
Your wife ?
What makes you believe it 's your wife ?
Probably his sense of humor .
Don 't come lurking around my home anymore !
You hear me ?
Shove your threats up your ass !
It 's my wife !
My wife !
I warned you !
What 's your problem ?
Isn 't it great to have Bartel 's soup again !
Eat slowly ! Slowly !
Let 's live our life as before .
You want to ?
Do you want to ?
Be careful ! It 's dripping everywhere .
You know , I thought it over .
We 're going to start the inn up again .
You 'll sing , of course , and perhaps I 'll do the opening act .
" I don 't want to worry you ,
" but the table-football players are running away ! "
Let 's surprise him !
I found Bella , my girlie !
That 's wonderful , Boris .
I did as you said . I was obstinate and I found Bella .
" I was obstinate and I found Bella ! "
Let 's have a drink !
Let 's make a toast ! To miracles that unite us at Christmas !
I was obstinate ...
" and I found Bella ! "
How does she look ?
She looks great ! It 's wonderful !
Oh , Bella !
I also think you re wonderful !
Are you alright , Mr. Bartel ?
Yes , yes ... I 'm fine .
Bella came back home , Gloria came back home ...
We 're all together for Christmas .
I love you . You ' re my family .
Hear that , my pooch , we 're family !
Oh , my darling pup !
Don 't you dare move !
Help me !
Come help me !
I don 't want to die !
I got him , Dad ! Let 's go !
- What 's happening ? - Shut up , bitch !
Sing !
I said sing !
Better than that !
Sparkling with desire
You are too beautiful and sensual
For a boy like me
I have a simple dream
Of serene happiness
That you won 't give ...
Don 't cry , Daddy !
Go on !
Yeah , go on !
Go on ! Go on ! Go on !
Shut up !
Why did you come back , Gloria ?
I loved you !
I 'm not Gloria !
I 'm Marc Stevens !
I 'm just a singer !
Liar !
Damn liar !
You left like a slut , you 'll pay like a slut !
You want to fuck her ?
Then fuck her !
Don 't touch my doggy , or I 'll kill you all !
Run , run !
- Let 's go ! - Go , Lars ! Find the slut !
Find the slut !
Well ?
It 's the marsh !
We have to get her !
After , do what you want with her !
Come on !
Why ...
Why 'd you come back , Gloria ?
If you loved me just a little ?
You did love me , didn 't you ?
Tell me that you loved me !
Say it !
Louder !
I loved you .
Subtitling : B.B. COM - Paris